YANNIS

WEN

CONTACT INFO

E-mail yannis.wen@gmail.com

Phone Nr +33 604032989

Address 87 Chapelgate, Dublin, D09 YD59

Portfolio wyannis.github.io

ABOUT ME

Senior Data Analyst from the adtech industry with over **3 years of work experience**. Expert at uncovering insights behind users' behaviors and turning them into

business value.

Comfortable working at the interface of multiple functions such as Product, Sales and Marketing and interacting with diverse stakeholders.

Engineering graduate from **École Polytechnique** and MSc Business Analytics graduate from the **University of Edinburgh**.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DATA ANALYST - AGENCY REVENUE STRATEGY

2024-NOW

CRITEO | Paris

- Delivering forecast analysis to support commercial pitches of retailers such as Currys, ASOS, ASDA, Macy's that would generate 8M€ in yearly revenue
- Growing the Commerce Audiences product from **6k€** to **18k€** of monthly revenue
- Developing **prescriptive analytics** to identify top advertiser prospects for each category of audience
- Creating processes and tools to enhance the sales of audiences to Agencies (used more than **100 times/month**)

DATA ANALYST - MEDIA OWNERS MONETIZATION

2021-2023

CRITEO | Paris

- Analytics for CRITEO's EMEA media owners (150M€ in quarterly revenue)
- Conduct of A/B test analyses to optimize the monetization of publishers
- Providing analytical insights to support strategical sales pitches
- Delivering dashboards that meet stakeholders' needs and highlight KPIs
- Escalating market feedback to the Product team and suggesting improvements
- Provided day-to-day operational support through data (300 issues solved)

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN - MARKETING ANALYTICS

2020

Mars & Co. | Paris

- Designed and implemented several statistical marketing attribution models with Python (Shapley values, Markov chains, Linear model)
- Worked on the large online sales data of the french theme park Futuroscope

EDUCATION

MSC IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS

2020-2021

Edinburgh University | Edinburgh, Scotland, UK

- Graduated with Distinction
- Dissertation topic: "Using NLP sentiment analysis to identify which writing style performs best for marketing emails of hotels"

DIPLÔME D'INGÉNIEUR

2017-2020

École Polytechnique | Palaiseau (Paris), France

• Majors: Computer Science and Economics

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Python, SQL, Tableau

● ○ ○ Excel, Powerpoint, HTML

● ○ ○ R, JavaScript

OTHER SKILLS

Project management

- Solid stakeholder management
- Storytelling
- Excellent communication

Languages

- French (native)
- English (full professional proficiency)
- German (intermediate)
- Chinese (basic)